## Lynda Foster

lyndabrf@gmail.com | Phone | Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github | Burbank, CA

## **SUMMARY**

I am an Employer Services analyst that excels in client-facing roles and optimizes productivity by automating redundant processes. In my spare time, I volunteer as a Software Developer, contributing to the modification and extension of a nonprofit's web applications. Academic and project experience includes 2 years object-oriented programming, 1 year .NET/C# web development, and 2 years SQL and database administration.

## **SKILLS**

- Languages: C# | JavaScript
- Frameworks: ASP.NET Core (MVC Web App/API, Class Library) | Entity Framework Core
- Databases: SQL | PostgreSQL | MS SQL Server
- Cloud Application Platforms: GitHub | Heroku | Splunk | Azure
- Other: HTML | CSS | Regex | Bootstrap | Postman | Swagger

## **EDUCATION**

MSc in Data Analytics | Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, UT Technologies: Machine Learning and Data Mining via SQL (Oracle 12c), Python (Jupyter), R (R-Studio), and SAS. Data Visualization in Excel and Tableau.

BSc in Computer Science | Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, UT Technologies: C++ (Visual Studio), Java (NetBeans and Eclipse), Python (PySpark), MySQL, Machine Learning, Web Development

- Co-created a 8,700+ member community of WGU Computer Science students to foster an environment of student mentoring, resource sharing, and support.
- Authored study guides that are currently distributed as a resource by program coordinators, course instructors, and students.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Recovering From Religion, Kansas City, KS | Web Developer (Volunteer) | 06/2022 - Present

- Reviewed, analyzed, developed, and modified existing Typescript (Node and React) repositories that utilized GitHub to track issues, review pull requests, and resolve merge conflicts.
- Participated in weekly stand-ups with a team of 5 other developers to maintain, manage, and extend the management and chat web applications in an agile setting.
- Coordinated with end users to ensure requirements for features are appropriately documented and efficiently implemented.

Benefit Plans Inc, Los Angeles, CA | Employer Services Analyst | 01/2019 - Present

- Developed, implemented, and maintained digital operational procedures that manage \$100M+ in monthly contribution payments to pre-taxed PH&W (pension, health, and welfare) benefit accounts.
- Produced the training knowledge base for the Employer Services department which expedited the onboarding of new employees.

# Lynda Foster

 Eliminated 40% of the processing time needed to reconcile discrepancies by automating the conversion of raw data to readable format using Excel macros and PowerShell scripts.

B'nai Hayim, Sherman Oaks, CA | Technical Coordinator | 04/2018 - 09/2019

- Established a system for financial reporting, database management, and website maintenance to facilitate the merging of two separate organizations.
- Created a knowledge base to train non-technical staff to independently update their website/database, maintain financial records, reconcile bank accounts, and create monthly financial reports using Quickbooks Online.
- Normalized csv data into 1st normal form for migration into an established relational database.

## PROJECTS | Portfolio

## Ifost42/brailleAPI

- .NET REST API, manages a database of ascii braille special symbols as defined by the International Council on English Braille.
- Swagger documentation follows Open API Specification standards.
- Implements Repository and Data Access Object design patterns.

#### Ifost42/blog | Website

- ASP.NET Full stack web application, used as a knowledge base of .NET(C#) coding and web development articles.
- Implements identity/role based access and rendering to limit article permissions to the owner while allowing users to leave comments.
- Google SMTP email service verifies user registration and forwards contact form submissions to the owner.
- Code-first approach using Entity Framework Core and PostgreSQL.

## Ifost42/Franchise | Website

- ASP.NET Full stack web application that evaluates the coverage health of a franchise by determining which locations (in a provided csv file) are farthest apart.
- Explores Kruskal's Minimum Spanning Tree to filter locations that can pass through other locations.
- Leveraged Unit tests (TDD) to manage scope changes as the app evolved over time.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (in progress) | Splunk Core Power User | ITIL Foundation in IT Service Management | Oracle Database SQL Certified Associate 1Z0-071